

#### online

http://blog.wtf.sg fb://shawntan.171287 shawntan@github tanshawn@linkedin

## languages

english (proficient) mandarin

## programming

Python, JavaScript, Java, Ruby, C, Perl

#### technical skills

HTML & CSS, LATEX, Linux System Administration

or Tan Jing Shan, Shawn 

✓ DOB: 17/12/1987 (a) (+65) 93877026

#### about

I currently work in the NUS Speech Recognition Group as a Research Assistant. I enjoy working on machine learning projects, and keeping up with the latest in neural networks research. I came in 3<sup>rd</sup> during the Quora Codesprint Machine Learning challenge in 2013 and maintain a blog where I write about my machine learning projects.

### research interests

artificial intelligence, recurrent neural networks, machine learning, reinforcement learning, graphical models, natural language processing, data mining

# **experience**

#### 2014-present Speech Recognition Group, NUS

Research Assistant

Manpower Officer

Research/Teaching Assistant

Working on the machine learning aspects of speech recognition using neural networks, with applications to speaker adaptation and noise robustness.

2013 - 2014 Semantics3

Software/Data Engineer

- Classification of products into a hierarchical taxonomy using a cascading naive bayes model built using the Lucene index.
- Name equivalency model used as part of the disambiguation process to determine if two product names are referring to the same thing.
- Experimented with using conditional random fields for attribute extraction from product names.

2010 - 2012 Web Information Retrieval and NLP Group (WING), NUS Undergraduate researcher Did two undergraduate research projects (see next page)

2008 - 2009 Singapore Armed Forces

01 - 06 2007 RHyMeS Center, Ngee Ann Polytechnic

Administrative position managing National Servicemen

- Provided technical support for students working on the RHyMeS project.
- Facilitated workshops on using the RHyMeS SDK and API.
- Taught students working on their projects how to use the Java Swing UI API

## education

2009 - 2012 **Bachelors of Computing (BComp)** 

National University of Singapore

Major in Computer Science - Upper 2<sup>nd</sup> Class Honours Special Programme in Computing (Turing Programme)

Focus Area: Artificial Intelligence

CAP: 4.39 / 5

2004 - 2007 **Diploma in Information Technology** 

Ngee Ann Polytechnic, Singapore

Specialisation in Software Engineering - Diploma with Merit

GPA: 3.8 / 4

2003 GCE '0' Levels

Mayflower Secondary School, Singapore

# projects

10 2014 **Neural Turing Machines implementation in Theano** 

Implementation of system described in "Neural Turing Machines." by Alex Graves, Greg

Wayne, and Ivo Danihelka.

2012 **Predicting Web 2.0 Thread Updates** 

> A method to estimate arrival times of new posts to forum discussion threads and an evaluation metric for measuring the effectiveness of an incremental crawler of a site with

time-sensitive data.

04 2012 **Focused Web Crawling using Markov Decision Processes** 

Using the least-squares policy iteration algorithm and some heuristics to perform focused

crawling. For CS4246R Al for Planning and Decision Making (Research Project)

2010 - 2011 grabsmart: A User-centric Web Information Extraction System

An integrated system that allows users to easily select portions of a page to extract, and

subsequently extracts the data in a manner that is robust to site layout changes.

04 2011 **LSPI Tetris Agent** 

> Application of the least-squares policy iteration algorithm to play Tetris as part of the CS3243 Introduction to Artificial Intelligence course. The agent can complete 100,000

lines on average, and up to a maximum of about a million lines.

# organisations

2010 - 2012 NUS Hackers

Coreteam Member (Member of Executive Committee)

weekly tech talk), and maintaining the download.nus.edu.sg mirror service.

2003 - 2012 **Singapore Scouts Association**  Assistant Venture Scout Leader

Attached to the Mayflower Secondary School Boy Scouts Group. Duties a include facil-

Duties include facilitating NUS Hacker activities: Hack & Roll 2012, Friday Hacks (a

itating camps, weekly meetings, and mentoring both scouts and ventures.